<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

   <statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
     <statement id="1">I feel like I can show a different side of myself when I speak in another language.</statement>
     <statement id="2">I feel connected and familiar when I hear people speak in a foreign language I know.</statement>
     <statement id="3">I think that I can express ideas in other languages that I can’t in Chinese or English.</statement>
     <statement id="4">Everyone can speak English today so I think there is not much point learning other languages.</statement>
     <statement id="5">It’s hard to see whether and how I will use French/German/Japanese in the future.</statement>
     <statement id="6">Learning English well is important for my future education.</statement>
     <statement id="7">Learning French/German/Japanese well is important for my future education.</statement>
     <statement id="8">I learn French/German/Japanese mainly for pleasure rather than practicality.</statement>
     <statement id="9">I study foreign languages because I want to make friends with people from all over the world.</statement>
     <statement id="10">Speaking several foreign languages will always be an important part of my identity even after I leave school.</statement>
     <statement id="11">I study French/German/Japanese because I want to be a multilingual person rather than I love the language per se.</statement>
     <statement id="12">In China, fluency in several foreign languages will give me a competitive edge over people who can only speak English and their mother tongue.</statement>
     <statement id="13">For me, foreign language skills are tools to achieve more important goals.</statement>
     <statement id="14">I’m proud to be able to speak more than one language.</statement>
     <statement id="15">I am interested in foreign cultures in general.</statement>
     <statement id="16">With internet and translation apps, it’s hard to see the point of learning foreign languages.</statement>
     <statement id="17">My experience in learning English does make my French/German/Japanese learning easier.</statement>
     <statement id="18">My experience in learning French/German/Japanese makes my English learning easier.</statement>
     <statement id="19">I prioritize learning English over French/German/Japanese.</statement>
     <statement id="20">I believe that I have a talent in language learning in general.</statement>
     <statement id="21">I would like to continue English learning even if it was not required by school curriculum.</statement>
     <statement id="22">I would like to continue French/German/Japanese learning even if it was not required by school curriculum.</statement>
     <statement id="23">I don’t enjoy learning foreign languages yet I still want to learn them well because FL skills are useful for my future.</statement>
     <statement id="24">I don’t enjoy learning foreign languages yet I still want to learn them well for the sake of degree.</statement>
     <statement id="25">I study hard in foreign languages because this is what a language-major student should do.</statement>
     <statement id="26">I think some languages are more important to learn than others.</statement>
     <statement id="27">Learning foreign languages is helpful to understanding people from French/German/Japanese-speaking countries.</statement>
     <statement id="28">Learning foreign languages facilitates me with better developed social network.</statement>
     <statement id="29">I’m looking forward to a better multicultural and multilingual outlook in the future.</statement>
     <statement id="30">I’m energized whenever I imagine the vision of achieving my goals in the future.</statement>
     <statement id="31">The more challenging the task is, the more I’m motivated to accomplish it.</statement>
     <statement id="32">Sometimes I would doubt the meaning of my goal/vision and thus result in a downward motivation.</statement>
     <statement id="33">Tracking daily attendance would help me to stick to the learning better.</statement>
     <statement id="34">When the daily schedule is discontinued one day, I would fail to follow it for the following several days.</statement>
     <statement id="35">The achievement of sub-goals renders me a sense of accomplishment and pleasure, which is an incentive for me to invest more in learning.</statement>
     <statement id="36">It is inspiring for me if my teachers and classmates provide positive feedback on my language learning.</statement>
     <statement id="37">Winning scholarship will yield my higher motivation to learn foreign languages.</statement>
     <statement id="38">The positive emotions I experience in learning (e.g., satisfaction, pleasure, accomplishment) generate my higher motivation to learn foreign languages.</statement>
     <statement id="39">When I’m in a bad mood, I have less motivation to learn foreign languages, and sometimes even stop learning.</statement>
     <statement id="40">I am more motivated to learn foreign languages when I face stress and anxiety.</statement>
     <statement id="41">My motivation of learning foreign languages diminishes when receiving negative feedbacks from others for my academic performance.</statement>
     <statement id="42">When I am challenged by others, a strengthened motivation of language learning will be generated because I desire to prove myself.</statement>
     <statement id="43">I feel demotivated during a crisis of interpersonal relationship (e.g., friendship).</statement>
     <statement id="44">I have a sensitive personality and would easily get anxious and depressed, which causes relatively large fluctuations in the intensity of my motivation.</statement>
     <statement id="45">I have a wide range of interests and enjoy taking up challenges, so I’m more motivated when facing with challenges in learning.</statement>
     <statement id="46">Overall, I consider myself to be a conscientious person characterized by being success-oriented, persistent and diligent, who is able to maintain motivation at a stable level.</statement>
     <statement id="47">When I encounter difficulties in learning, encouragement and expectations from friends, teachers and families help a lot in maintaining my motivation and overcoming the difficulties.</statement>
     <statement id="48">Having peers to study with and monitor each other will sustain and booster my motivation.</statement>
     <statement id="49">Being aware of the gap between me and my classmates will improve my motivation to learn foreign languages to narrow the gap.</statement>
     <statement id="50">I get easily distracted seeing peers around me having fun, and my motivation to learn foreign languages will be weakened.</statement>
     <statement id="51">Teachers’ teaching style does exert a positive impact on my motivation.</statement>
     <statement id="52">I am sensitive to surroundings and need to be in a place like a library to stay focused and motivated.</statement>
     <statement id="53">I am more motivated to learn foreign languages when seeing my classmates studying hard.</statement>
     <statement id="54">I am more motivated to learn foreign languages when I have a large block of time free to organize.</statement>
     <statement id="55">When I find the knowledge taught by teachers significantly different from what I have expected, I may feel disappointed and demotivated in learning foreign languages.</statement>
     <statement id="56">The learning habits I developed in primary and secondary school play an important role in sustaining my motivation of foreign language learning in college.</statement>
     <statement id="57">Learning a third language (or another new language) will reduce my commitment to learning English.</statement>
     <statement id="58">I will be more motivated to learn foreign languages after relaxation (e.g., after shopping/playing games).</statement>
     <statement id="59">I don’t want to show people around me that I have strong motivation to learn foreign languages, so sometimes I would suppress it deliberately.</statement>
     <statement id="60">I feel pressured to study foreign languages well, because I think people around me will be disappointed if I didn’t.</statement>
   </statements>